Finding Aid for Jane Lockwood Barney papers
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Personal Files
  - Correspondence
    - Falletich, Thomas L., 1994-2003 (Box 11)
      (from the St. Andrew's Job Intern Program)
    - Family Email, 1995-2001 (Box 11)
    - Guthrie, Doris and Harvey, 1995-2004 (Box 11)
    - Harding, Brent, 2001-2006 (Box 11)
      (from the Prison Creative Arts Program)
    - Jones, C., 1994-2000 (Box 11)
    - Kay, Joshua and Hatcher, Carolyn, 2000 (Box 11)
    - Ketchin, Jane and Susan, 1993-2001 (Box 11)
    - Lahti, Dianne, 1996-1998 (Box 11)
    - Lapidos, Carole, 1991-1999 (scattered) (Box 11)
    - Legal Services of South East Michigan, 1999 (Box 11)
    - Martin, Bill, 1995-1997 (Box 11)
    - Maynard, Libby, 1997-2000 (Box 11)
    - McCabe, Carole, 1999 (Box 11)
    - Miscellaneous Letters, 1952-2007 (scattered) (Box 11)
    - Murdoch, Jean K., 1980-1999 (scattered) (Box 11)
    - Power, Phil, 1989-1990 (Box 11)
      (regarding the UM Geriatric Center)
    - Rivers, (Congresswoman) Lynn, 1994-2002 (scattered) (Box 11)
    - Washtenaw Affordable Housing Corporation (WAHC), 1987-1988; 1997 (Box 11)
    - Winter, Sara, 1999-2001 (Box 11)
    - Wiss, Lia, 2002 (Box 11)
    - Ziel, Hermann, 1974-1984 (Box 11)
  - Education
    - Diplomas, 1937-1970 (Folder 1)
      (includes Phi Kappa Phi membership certificate)
    - Union Theological Seminary, 1940-2003 (Box 12)
    - University Center for Adult Education, 1966 (Box 12)
    - University of Michigan School of Social Work, 1968-1971 (Box 12)
    - Wellesley, 1981-2005 (Box 12)
  - Family
    - Barney Genealogy, 1982; 2008 (Box 12)
    - Danny Barney, 1959-1961 (Box 12)
      (includes 2 folders of The Parishfield News written by Danny)
    - Reverend Roger Barney, 1951-1968 (Box 12)
  - Political Affiliation
    - African Americans for Gore, 2000 (Box 12)
    - Ann Arbor Democratic Party, 1986-1999 (Box 12)
    - City Council Democrats, 1993 (Box 12)
    - Hillary Rodham Clinton Fan Club (HRCFC) of Ann Arbor, 1996-1998 (Box 12)
    - Kolb, Chris, 2000 (Box 12)
      (53rd District State Representative)
    - Michigan Democratic Party, 1995-1999 (Box 12)
    - The Michigan Prospect, 1998 (Box 12)
    - Pollack, Lana, 1989-1994 (Box 12)
      (Senator)
    - Turnham, Hollis, undated (Box 12)
      (John Heinz Senate Fellow)
    - Ward 5 -- Election and Campaign Planning
      - 1993-1995 (Box 12)
      - 2000-2001 (Box 12)
      - Kentucky Derby Plan, 1994 (Box 12)
    - Washtenaw Democratic Party, 1996-2000 (Box 12)
    - Wheeler-Smith, Alma, 1996 (Box 12)
      (State Senator)
  - Assisted Living
    - Chelsea Community Hospital, undated (Box 12)
      (Barney was hospitalized here for a period of time)
    - Glacier Hills, 2001 (Box 12)
      (Barney's Chosen Assisted Living Home)
    - National Citizens' Coalition for Nursing Home Reform, 2005 (Box 12)
    - University Commons, 1999-2002 (Box 12)
      (Correspondence and Pamphlets)
  - Awards and Recognitions
    - American College of Healthcare Administrators (ACHCA) Awards, 1984 (Box 12)
    - Award for Servant Leadership in Building a Beloved and Just Community, January 2008 (Box 12)
    - Celebration of Women, 1997 (Box 12)
    - Community Councils Association (CCA) Retirement, 1986 (Box 12)
    - Homeless Awareness Week, 2003 (Box 12)
    - Washtenaw Community College Recognition Award Ceremony, Turner Clinic, and Dr. Ivan Duff, 1992 (Box 12)
      (cassette tape)
    - Articles Featuring Jane L. Barney (Box 12)
      - "Does It Have To Be This Way? Research in Gerontology," Research News, November / December 1975 Vol. 26 Nos. 5/6 (Box 12)
        (Barney featured on pages 11-13)
      - "Jane Barney: What does she like best? People," Ann Arbor Today, No. 3, Fall 1993 (Box 12)
      - Medicine at Michigan, Fall 2007 (Box 12)
        (Barney featured on pages 18-19)
      - University of Michigan Institute of Gerontology Annual Report (Box 12)
        - 1984-1985 (Box 12)
          (Barney featured on last page)
        - 1986-1987 (Box 12)
          (Barney featured in Public Service Program section)
        - 1987-1988 (Box 12)
      - Other Honors, 1990-2001 (scattered) (Box 12)
      - Turner African American Services Council, 1999 (Box 12)
  - Photographs
    - 80th Birthday Weekend Event, 1994 (Box 12)
    - Area Agency on Aging 1-B Award Ceremony, Summer 1999 (Box 12)
    - Miscellaneous Photographs (Box 12)
    - New Hope / University of Michigan Geriatric Clinic Groundbreaking Ceremony, 2001 (Box 12)
    - Washtenaw County Bar Association Liberty Bell Award, April 1997 (Box 12)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Materials
    - Aging, Nos. 233-234, March-April 1974 (Box 12)
    - Episcopal Theological School Journal (Box 12)
    - Vol. 7, No. 2, 1962 (Box 12)
    - Vol. 7, No. 3, 1962 (Box 12)
    - Images of Old Age in America: 1970 to the Present, 1978 (Box 12)
    - University of Michigan School of Public Health Task Force on Racial and Cultural Concerns -- A Report of Student Concerns About Issues of Race and Racism in the School of Public Health, 1990 (Box 12)
Related material
The Roger Warren Barney and Jane Lockwood Barney papers, 1929-2002 (call number 2008125 Aa 2) includes Jane Barney material that was primarily acquired by the Bentley Library with the papers of her husband, Roger Warren Barney, and contains mostly Jane Barney material dated before 1978, the year of Roger Warren Barney's death. Jane Lockwood Barney series (ca. 1.5 linear feet) includes personal files and material related to various organizations. Also included in this collection is family correspondence.